property.ie 2019-02-12

# Privacy & Cookies - Property.ie

Last updated on 16th May, 2018

### Contents

**1\. Privacy Policy**  
**2\. Cookie policy.**

## Privacy Policy

## Introduction

Your privacy is important to us. This privacy policy has been created to explain how and why we collect and use information about our users, and how we manage your privacy protection. We recommend that you read this statement in full, so that you understand how we will use your personal data. You can also read about specific issues by clicking on one of the topics below. 

### Table of Contents

**1\. What personal data do we collect?**  
**2\. Legal basis for processing.**  
**3\. How do we use your personal data?**  
**4\. How do we share your information?**  
**5\. Your rights and choices.**  
**6\. Other important information.**  

## What personal data do we collect?

Daft collects personal data to operate our business and to provide you with the product and services that we offer. You provide some of this data to us directly, for example when you open an account with us, contact an advertiser on the site, or send a query to our support team. Other data is collected when you interact with our products, by using cookies and other technologies. 

When using our site, you have choices about what data we collect, and when you are asked to provide personal data you may decline. If you decline to provide data that is necessary to provide you with a particular product or feature, you may not be able to use this product or feature. 

We collect personal data in the following ways: 

## 1\. Through information you provide to us.

When you register with us as a user, you provide us with some personal data such as your name and email address, which we will store in order to create your account. We will also store information relating to any further use of our service, when you contact another user of the site through our platform, the contents of the emails you send to them and any other information that you may upload to the Sites. Finally, we may also collect information from any correspondence that you have with us. 

## 2\. Through your use of our services.

When you use our services, we collect information about what types of services you use and how you use them. For example, which parts of our websites you visit, and what advertisements you view. The information that we collect while you use our services can be grouped into the following categories: 

  * _Information about your device and internet connection_

Using technical logs and other tools, we register information about the device you use, such as the device manufacturer, operating systems and browser version. We also collect information about the connection to our services, such as IP address, network ID, cookies and unique ID files. This information can help us to adapt the way content is displayed to you, based on your device and user profile. 

  * _Information about how our services are used_

We also register information about how you use our services. For example, which pages of the site you visit, the searches that you have performed, the times and dates that you visited our site, how long a page is displayed on your screen, how you navigate around the page, which websites you have visited before visiting our site, what functions you have carried out on a page, and if you have completed a transaction. 

  * _Cookies and other locally stored content_

When you use our services, cookies and other data are stored locally on your device. These cookies provide us with information that we can then read. You can find more information about cookies, how and why we use them, and how to manage them in our cookie policy. 

  * _Information about user location_

We register your geographical location based on your IP address and mobile network code. 

  * _Messages_

We collect information about when you send or receive messages from other users of our site. 

## 3\. Through other sources.

We receive information from third parties where you use their services to log into our site, for example, if you log in using Facebook or Twitter. 

## Legal Basis for Processing

We process your Personal Data in order to ensure the necessary performance of your contract with us. In certain circumstances, we may also process your Personal Data for the purposes of our legitimate interests, such as to inform you of changes to our services, to provide you with information about other services we offer, or in order to comply with any legal obligations to which we are subject. 

We may also rely upon your consent as a relevant legal basis for processing your Personal Data. In the event you wish to withdraw your consent to the collection and processing of your Personal Data in this manner, please follow the links below: 

  1. [My Profile](https://www.daft.ie/my-daft/account-settings/)

## How We Use Your Personal Data

We use the data that we collect to provide you with the products and services that we offer. This allows us to improve the products that we offer you and to personalise your experience on our site. We may also use the data to communicate with you, to inform you about your account and to provide you with security updates. Where you have consented for us to do so, we may also use your data to contact you in relation to updates about our own products, products provided by third parties, and to help to show you more relevant adverts on the site. 

Your data will be used by us to authenticate your account and to enable you to interact with other users of our site. 

  * _Contacting advertisers_

When you contact an advertiser though our site, we will use the personal data that you have provided as part of this contact to connect you to the advertiser. The advertiser will receive a copy of any data that you have entered as part of your message to them. 

  * _Communications_

We will contact you via email and messages posted on our website or apps. These messages will communicate about service related issues and security updates. Where you have consented for us to do you, we will also contact you with promotional marketing materials from us and from our partners. You can update your marketing preferences at any time within your account. Please note that it will not be possible to opt out of receiving service messages from us. This includes messages relating to security and legal notices. We may issue marketing materials to the properties that are listed on our platform for the purposes of advertising our services to the occupiers of such properties. 

  * _Advertising_

Banner advertising on our site is targeted to visitors of the site through a variety of ad networks and exchanges. We also use this data to measure the performance of these adverts. We use the data that you provide to us, through your cookie preferences, either separately or combined to achieve this. 

  * _Research and Developing Our Services_

We use data that we collect through your use of our site and through public feedback, to conduct research and develop our services based on our findings. This allows us to provide you with a better experience when using our site. 

  * _Customer Support_

We use the data that you provide to us, including your communications, to investigate and respond to service issues and complaints. 

  * _Insights_

We use your data to generate statistics about our site that do not identify you. These statistics provide us information about how our site is used, the number of ad impressions served or clicked on, and the demographic distribution of visitors to our site. 

  * _Security Monitoring and Investigations_

We will use your data when necessary to investigate and identify possible fraudulent behaviour on the site and possible attempts to harm other members or visitors to the site. We will also use your data to investigate violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy. 

## How we Share Your Information

We retain access to all personal information that we have collected from you. If you have consented on signup or on the appropriate email form, we may provide any of the information we collect to carefully screened third parties to contact you regarding products or services that we think may be of interest to you. If Daft enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed to our new business partners or owners. 

  * _Our Services_

Our service allows you to engage with other members of our site. If you send a message to another member of our site, your message will be shared with that site member. If you comment on an advert, or leave feedback on the account of another person, these will be publicly visible on our site. 

  * _Service Providers_

We engage other service providers to help us to provide our service to you. For example, to process payments, site maintenance and fraud detection. These service providers will have access to your information as much as is reasonably necessary for them to perform these tasks on our behalf. They are obligated not to disclose or use your data for any other purpose. 

  * _Legal Disclosures_

When required to by law, we may disclose information about you. This may be as the result of a subpoena or other legal process. Your personal information will also be shared if we believe that the disclosure is necessary to 

    1. Be used by government enforcement agencies investigate, prevent or take action against any suspected or actual illegal activities.
    2. To enforce the agreements that we have with you.
    3. To investigate and defend Daft against any allegations made by third parties.
    4. To protect the integrity and security of our services.
    5. To exercise the rights and safety of Daft, our employees and other users of our service.
  * _Change of Ownership_

If Daft enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed to our new business partners or owners in preparation for, or as a result of, any of these events. Any other entity which buys Daft or any part of our business, will have the right to continue to use your data in the way described by this privacy policy, unless you consent otherwise. 

## Your Rights and Choices

The General Data Protection Regulations offer you a number of rights in relation to your data. This includes the right to access a copy of your data, a right to receive a copy of your data that can be transferred to another organisation, a right to data deletion, a right to withdraw your consent to data processing, a right to restrict the processing of your data, and information on any automated decision making processes. 

  * _Data Retention_

The amount of time that we retain data for, depends on the type of data being retained, and how that is used. In some cases, there will be a legal requirement for us to hold data for a specified amount of time. In other cases, we will not retain the data for any longer than necessary for the purpose that it was collected and processed. 

When you register an account with us, we will retain the information that you provide to us for as long as you hold this account. Once an account has been closed, we will continue to retain this data for a period of seven years. This timeframe is in line with the Irish statutory limitation periods. If you don't actively close your account with us, it automatically become inactive after 3 months of you not accessing it. After this, the data you have provided us will be retained for seven years. 

If you have provided data to us without registering an account, this data will be retained for 7 years after your last date of activity with us. 

  * _Right to Access Your Personal Data_

Non- registered and registered users of the Sites can request we provide them with a copy of the personally identifiable information we hold by using our data request feature. 

  * _Right to Control Your Personal Data_

Registered users of our site can update their information by using our data request feature or contacting our Customer Support Team directly. You can also edit and make changes to the personal information by logging into your account and editing it directly from there. You can change your marketing and contact preferences at any time in your account dashboard by opting out receiving of these communications. You may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that such information is accurate and kept up-to-date. 

  * _Right to Data Deletion_

Non- registered and registered users of our sites can request we delete any personally identifiable information we hold by using our data request feature. In some instances we may be unable to delete your data if we are required to retain it to comply with our legal obligations (including requests from law enforcement agencies). 

  * _Right to Data Portability_

Registered users of our site have the right to data portability. This means that you can request that a copy of your data is made available in a structured, commonly used and machine readable form that can be transferred to you or to another organisation. You may request a portable copy of your data by using our data request feature. 

## Other Important Information

  * _Special Category Personal Data_

Daft does not collect any special categories of personal data. However, if you enter this information into any free text section of our site, such as the ad description, or on our forums, this information will be held and processed in the same manner as all other data that you have provided to us. 

  * _Security_

The security of your data is important to us. We perform regular monitoring of our systems to identify possible vulnerabilities and attacks. However, we cannot warrant the security of any information that you send to us. No guarantee is given that the data will not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

  * _Direct marketing_

We will only send you marketing information where you have opted in to receive these communications. You can change your marketing preferences at any time, by logging into your account and changing this on your account dashboard. You can also opt out of receiving marketing at any time using the unsubscribe link that can be found at the end of each email that we send. 

  * _Changes to this Statement_

This statement will be updated when necessary to reflect changes that we make to our products. When this statement is updated, the "last updated" dated at the top of this statement will be changed. We will notify you of any changes to our privacy statement either by directly sending you a notification, or by posting a notification of the change on our site. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy regularly so that you can stay informed about our use of your data. 

  * _Contact information_

If you have any questions in relation to this Policy, please contact our Data Privacy Officer at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2246524d62464344560c4b47). You can also contact us by writing to 

Data Privacy Officer  
Distilled SCH  
Latin Hall  
Golden Lane  
Dublin 8. 

If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you have the right to contact your local Data Protection Commissioner. In Ireland, they can be contacted via their website [here](https://www.dataprotection.ie/). 

## Cookie Policy

## What are cookies and how are they used?

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier, that is sent to your deviceâ€™s web browser from a website's computer and is stored on your *device's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookies to your web browser. Your browser will have the option to prevent websites using cookies (your browser's help screen will tell you how to do this), but please note that this may reduce the functionality of our website and other websites. You can also change your targeted advertising cookie settings by visiting [Google's Ad Personalisation](https://adssettings.google.com/) and/or [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ie/).

Property.ie (the website) uses cookies to enable us to personalise your visits to our website, simplify the sign-in processes, remember your preferences, track the website's performance, deliver targeted advertising relevant to your interests and give you a better overall experience.

*PCs, tablets, mobile phones and any other internet accessible hardware, respectively.

## What types of cookies we use:

## Essential Cookies

These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms.

You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will then not work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.

## Functional Cookies

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.

## Analytics Cookies

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below:

Our Cookies  
---  
Name | Category | Description  
cookie_notice | Essential | This cookie is used to determine whether the cookie notice should be shown to a user or not. It expires 1 year after being set.  
daft_last_search | Essential |  This cookie stores the last search of the user. It's value is a json representation of last search filters used and it expires after 1 month.   
daft_uuid | Essential |  This cookie is an identifier in the form of a randomly-generated alphanumeric string which is used to identify a user session. It expires 6 years after the user's visit.   
daftID | Essential |  This cookie is an identifier in the form of a randomly-generated alphanumeric string which is used to identify a user session. It expires when the user ends the session.   
NPS_215a2284_last_seen | Essential |  This cookie is used to register when the NPS was last seen. It expires after 3 months.   
OPENSHIFT_production_search_SERVERID  | Essential |  This cookie is used to ensure that the users requests are dealt with by the same server and that relevant content is displayed to the user.   
phishing_notice | Essential |  This cookie is used to determine if the phishing notice should be shown to the user or not. A typical value is "true". It expires after the user ends the session.   
remember_me_user | Essential |  This cookie is used to save the login details of a user so that next time the user comes back using the same computer the user doesn't need to login again. This is set only if "Remember me" is checked by the user. It expires when the user logs out.   
strap_*_*  | Essential |  Straplines are horizontal bars at the top of our website which sometimes appear to display a message to the user. This cookie is used to control whether we show the strapline to the user or not. It expires after 3 years.   
unique | Essential |  This cookie consists of a date and randomly-generated alphanumeric string. It is used to show users custom content on our website based on their searches. It expires on Jan 1st, 6 years after the user's visit.   

## Targeting Cookies

These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners, e.g. DoubleClick by Google. They may be used to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites.

If you do not allow these cookies, you will still see the same number of advertisements, however they may be less relevant to you. These cookies will be on by default but can managed directly by visiting [Google's Ads Personalisation](https://adssettings.google.com/) and/or [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ie).

## Third Party Cookies

These cookies are set by entities other than the owner of the website you're visiting.

Some Property.ie web pages may contain content from other sites (e.g. playable files from a video sharing website), which may set their own cookies. Also, if you share a link to a Property.ie page, the service you share it on (e.g. social networks) may set a cookie on your browser.

Property.ie has no control over third party cookies.

You can find more information about the third party cookies on Daft.ie in the table below:

Third Party Cookies  
---  
Name | Category | Description  
ABTasty  
ABTasty | Functional |  This cookie is set by ABTasty. ABTasty is a platform for conversion rate optimization, personalization, customer activation, and testing. This cookie sends test data such as visitorID, test and variant IDs and timestamps. It lasts about 1 year.   
ABTastySession | Functional |  This cookie is set by ABTasty. ABTasty is a platform for conversion rate optimization, personalization, customer activation, and testing. This cookie identifies a unique session. It allows ABTasty to determine that a new session has begun for a user. It only lasts for the length of the session.   
ATInternet  
idrxvr | Analytics |  This cookie is set by ATInternet and collects anonymous information when you visit our site to enable the analysis of browsing behavior on the site for optimization. It expires after 1 year.   
Bing  
_uetsid | Targeting | This is Microsoft's Bing Ads Universal Event Tracking (UET) tracking cookie. It may be used to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant ads. The cookie works by uniquely identifying your browser and device. Learn more: [BingAds](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/remarketing-in-paid-search-policies). You can opt-out [here](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/opt-out-of-the-bing-ads-optimization-program)  
CloudFlare  
__cfduid | Functional |  This cookie is set by CloudFlare, a company that provides internet security services. It is used to apply security settings to protect users. It expires after 1 year.   
Google  
__gads | Targeting |  This cookie is associated with the DoubleClick for Publishers service from Google. It is used to register what ads have been shown to the user. You can set your Google Ads Personalization here: [Google Ads](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/) or it off here: [Ads Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ie/your-ad-choices)  
Google Analytics  
_ga | Analytics |  This cookie is associated with Google Universal Analytics. This cookie is used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly-generated number as a client identifier. It is used to calculate visitor, session and campaign data for our analytical reports. It expires after 2 years.   
_gid | Analytics |  This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics. It may store and update a unique value for each page visited. It expires after 1 day.   
HotJar  
_hjClosedSurveyInvites | Analytics |  This cookie is set once a visitor interacts with a Survey invitation modal popup. It is used to ensure that the same invite does not re-appear if it has already been shown. Lasts 365 days.   
_hjDonePolls | Analytics |  This cookie is set once a visitor completes a poll using the Feedback Poll widget. It is used to ensure that the same poll does not re-appear if it has already been filled in. Lasts 365 days   
_hjMinimizedPolls | Analytics |  This cookie is set once a visitor minimizes a Feedback Poll widget. It is used to ensure that the widget stays minimizes when the visitor navigates through your site. Lasts 365 days   
_hjDoneTestersWidgets | Analytics |  This cookie is set once a visitor submits their information in the Recruit User Testers widget. It is used to ensure that the same form does not re-appear if it has already been filled in. Lasts 365 days   
_hjMinimizedTestersWidgets | Analytics |  This cookie is set once a visitor minimizes a Recruit User Testers widget. It is used to ensure that the widget stays minimizes when the visitor navigates through the site. Lasts 365 days   
_hjIncludedInSample | Analytics |  This session cookie is set to let Hotjar know whether that visitor is included in the sample which is used to generate funnels. Lasts 365 days   
_hjShownFeedbackMessage | Analytics |  This cookie is set when a visitor minimizes or completes Incoming Feedback. This is done so that the Incoming Feedback will load as minimized immediately if they navigate to another page where it is set to show. Lasts 365 days.   
Tealium  
utag_main | Analytics |  This cookie name is associated with the Tealium data platform and is used for web analytics. It expires after 1 year.   
PageFair  
bm_daily_unique | Analytics |  This cookie is used to count the number of visitors to the website who use adblocking software. It expires at the end of the day.   
bm_last_load_status | Analytics |  This cookie is used to detect visitors who enable or disable their adblocking software.   
bm_monthly_unique | Analytics |  This cookie is used to count the number of visitors to the website who use adblocking software. It expires at the end of the month.   
bm_sample_frequency | Analytics |  This cookie is used to throttle requests to PageFair servers. It expires at the end of the day.   

## Your Choices

For more information on how to manage your cookie settings in respect of third party cookies please go to [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). If you are primarily concerned about third party cookies generated by advertisers, you can turn these off by going to [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ie/)

You can personalise the ads that Google serves here.

If, at any stage, we make amendments to our cookie policy, you will be notified and may be required to update your choices as a result.
